export default {
  id: 'jp_word_ms_noun_1_1_1',
  name: '일어달 명사 LV1-1 (100자 / 뜻)',
  data: [
    { question: '挨拶', answer: ['あいさつ', '인사'] },
    { question: '間', answer: ['あいだ', '동안, 동안에'] },
    { question: '相手', answer: ['あいて', '상대'] },
    { question: '愛用', answer: ['あいよう', '애용'] },
    { question: '青', answer: ['あお', '파랑'] },
    { question: '赤ちゃん', answer: ['あかちゃん', '아기'] },
    { question: '秋', answer: ['あき', '가을'] },
    { question: '顎', answer: ['あご', '턱'] },
    { question: '朝', answer: ['あさ', '아침'] },
    { question: '朝御飯', answer: ['あさごはん', '아침 식사'] },
    { question: '足', answer: ['あし', '발, 다리'] },
    { question: '味', answer: ['あじ', '맛'] },
    { question: '明日', answer: ['あした', '내일'] },
    { question: '頭', answer: ['あたま', '머리'] },
    { question: '後', answer: ['あと', '뒤, 나중'] },
    { question: '穴', answer: ['あな', '구멍, 결점, 약점'] },
    { question: '油', answer: ['あぶら', '기름'] },
    { question: '余り', answer: ['あまり', '나머지 / ~남짓 (명사 + あまい) / ~한 나머지 (~のあまり) / ~한 결과 (~したあまり)'] },
    { question: '雨', answer: ['あめ', '비'] },
    { question: '安心', answer: ['あんしん', '안심'] },
    { question: '家', answer: ['いえ', '집'] },
    { question: '息', answer: ['いき', '숨, 호흡'] },
    { question: '池', answer: ['いけ', '연못'] },
    { question: '意見', answer: ['いけん', '의견'] },
    { question: '居酒屋', answer: ['いざかや', '서민용 술집'] },
    { question: '石', answer: ['いし', '돌'] },
    { question: '医者', answer: ['いしゃ', '의사'] },
    { question: '以上', answer: ['いじょう', '이상'] },
    { question: '一日中', answer: ['いちにちじゅう', '하루 종일'] },
    { question: '一夜', answer: ['いちや', '하룻밤, 어느 날 밤'] },
    { question: '一緒', answer: ['いっしょ', '함께 함, 동시에 함'] },
    { question: '一足', answer: ['いっそく', '한 켤레'] },
    { question: '一杯', answer: ['いっぱい', '가득, 한잔'] },
    { question: '一方', answer: ['いっぽう', '오직 ~하기만 함, 오로지 ~함'] },
    { question: 'いとこ', answer: ['', '사촌'] },
    { question: '今', answer: ['いま', '지금, 방금'] },
    { question: '入口', answer: ['いりぐち', '입구'] },
    { question: '色', answer: ['いろ', '색, 낯빛'] },
    { question: '上', answer: ['うえ', '위쪽, 분야, ~상(건강상, 시기상)'] },
    { question: '受付', answer: ['うけつけ', '접수'] },
    { question: '後ろ', answer: ['うしろ', '뒤'] },
    { question: '内側', answer: ['うちがわ', '안쪽'] },
    { question: '腕', answer: ['うで', '팔, 솜씨'] },
    { question: 'うどん', answer: ['', '우동'] },
    { question: '馬', answer: ['うま', '말'] },
    { question: '海', answer: ['うみ', '바다'] },
    { question: '裏', answer: ['うら', '안, (야구의)~말'] },
    { question: '売り切れ', answer: ['うりきれ', '매진'] },
    { question: '売り場', answer: ['うりば', '매장'] },
    { question: '上着', answer: ['うわぎ', '상의, 겉옷'] },
    { question: '運転', answer: ['うんてん', '운전, (자금 등의)운용'] },
    { question: '絵', answer: ['え', '그림'] },
    { question: '映画', answer: ['えいが', '영화'] },
    { question: '駅員', answer: ['えきいん', '역무원'] },
    { question: '横断歩道', answer: ['おうだんほどう', '횡단보도'] },
    { question: '往復', answer: ['おうふく', '왕복'] },
    { question: '多く', answer: ['おおく', '수량이 많음, 대부분'] },
    { question: 'おかげで', answer: ['', '덕분에, 덕택에'] },
    { question: 'お代わり', answer: ['', '같은 음식을 더 먹음, 또는 그 음식'] },
    { question: '奥', answer: ['おく', '깊숙한 곳, 안, 속'] },
    { question: '奥歯', answer: ['おくば', '어금니'] },
    { question: '臆病', answer: ['おくびょう', '겁쟁이'] },
    { question: '教え方', answer: ['おしえかた', '가르치는 법'] },
    { question: '音', answer: ['おと', '(사물의) 소리'] },
    { question: '大人', answer: ['おとな', '어른'] },
    { question: '踊り', answer: ['おどり', '춤'] },
    { question: 'おなか', answer: ['', '배'] },
    { question: 'お巡りさん', answer: ['おまわりさん', '순경 아저씨'] },
    { question: '親', answer: ['おや', '부모'] },
    { question: '解決', answer: ['かいけつ', '해결'] },
    { question: '外国人', answer: ['がいこくじん', '외국인'] },
    { question: '会社', answer: ['かいしゃ', '회사'] },
    { question: '外出中', answer: ['がいしゅつちゅう', '외출중'] },
    { question: '開発', answer: ['かいはつ', '개발'] },
    { question: '回復', answer: ['かいふく', '회복'] },
    { question: '買い物', answer: ['かいもの', '장보기'] },
    { question: '顔', answer: ['かお', '얼굴, 표정, 안색'] },
    { question: '書留', answer: ['かきとめ', '등기'] },
    { question: '確認', answer: ['かくにん', '확인'] },
    { question: '傘', answer: ['かさ', '우산'] },
    { question: '火事', answer: ['かじ', '화재'] },
    { question: '風邪', answer: ['かぜ', '감기'] },
    { question: '風', answer: ['かぜ', '바람, 모습, 세상인심'] },
    { question: '家族', answer: ['かぞく', '가족'] },
    { question: '肩', answer: ['かた', '어깨'] },
    { question: '方', answer: ['かた', '한쪽'] },
    { question: '形', answer: ['かたち', '모양, 꼴, 형상, 형체'] },
    { question: '片道', answer: ['かたみち', '편도'] },
    { question: '月', answer: ['がつ', '월'] },
    { question: '楽器', answer: ['がっき', '악기'] },
    { question: '学校', answer: ['がっこう', '학교'] },
    { question: '角', answer: ['かど', '모퉁이'] },
    { question: '金持ち', answer: ['かねもち', '부자'] },
    { question: '雷', answer: ['かみなり', '천둥'] },
    { question: '体', answer: ['からだ', '몸'] },
    { question: '彼', answer: ['かれ', '그, 그 남자'] },
    { question: '関係', answer: ['かんけい', '관계'] },
    { question: '感じ', answer: ['かんじ', '느낌, 기분'] },
    { question: '気', answer: ['き', '기, 기력, 마음, 정신, 기분, 생각'] },
    { question: '木', answer: ['き', '나무'] }
  ]
}
